and you can call and leave him a message. And when you call and leave him a message, you just, on the outgoing message, it's just whale sounds and then a beep, which actually sounds a lot like a whale sound. And they get a picture of their whale too. So this is Randolph, and Randolph belongs to a kid named Nico who was one of the first kids to ever call in, and I'll play you some of Nico's message. This is the first message I ever got from Nico. (Audio) Nico: Hello, this is Nico. I am your owner, Randolph. Hello. So this is the first time I can ever talk to you, and I might talk to you soon another day. Bye. Mac Barnett: So Nico called back, like, an hour later. (Laughter) And here's another one of Nico's messages. (Audio) Nico: Hello, Randolph, this is Nico. I haven't talked to you for a long time, but I talked to you on Saturday or Sunday, yeah, Saturday or Sunday, so now I'm calling you again to say hello and I wonder what you're doing right now, and I'm going to probably call you again tomorrow or today, so I'll talk to you later. Bye. MB: So he did, he called back that day again. He's left over 25 messages for Randolph over four years. You find out all about him and the grandma that he loves and the grandma that he likes a little bit less — (Laughter) — and the crossword puzzles that he does, and this is — I'll play you one more message from Nico. This is the Christmas message from Nico. [Beep] (Audio) Nico: Hello, Randolph, sorry I haven't talked to you in a long time. It's just that I've been so busy because school started, as you might not know, probably, since you're a whale, you don't know, and I'm calling you to just say, to wish you a merry Christmas. So have a nice Christmas, and bye-bye, Randolph. Goodbye. MB: I actually got Nico, I hadn't heard from in 18 months, and he just left a message two days ago. His voice is completely different, but he put his babysitter on the phone, and she was very nice to Randolph as well. But Nico's the best reader I could hope for. I would want anyone I was writing for to be in that place emotionally with the things that I create. I feel lucky. Kids like Nico are the best readers, and they deserve the best stories we can give them. Thank you very much. (Applause)
en el que puedes dejarle mensajes. Y cuando uno llama y le deja mensajes, en el mensaje de respuesta se oyen sonidos de ballena y un bip, que también se parece a sonido de ballena. Y también reciben una foto de su ballena. Este es Randolph, Randolph pertenece a Nico uno de los primeros niños que llamó; les pasaré algunos de los mensajes de Nico. Este es el primer mensaje que recibí de Nico. (Audio) Nico: Hola, soy Nico. Soy tu dueño, Randolph. Hola. Es la primera vez que te hablo, pronto puedo hablarte otra vez. Adiós. Mac Barnett: Nico llamó otra vez, como una hora después. (Risas) Otro mensaje de Nico. (Audio) Nico: Hola, Randolph, soy Nico. No hemos hablado hace mucho tiempo, te llamé el sábado o domingo, sí, sábado o domingo, por eso te llamo otra vez para saludarte y preguntarte qué estás haciendo ahora, probablemente te llamaré otra vez hoy o mañana, te llamo más tarde. Adiós. MB: Lo hizo, llamó otra vez ese día. Dejó 25 mensajes para Randolph en 4 años. Allí está todo sobre él, la abuela que ama, la abuela que quiere un poco menos... (Risas) los crucigramas que hace, y... les pasaré otro mensaje de Nico. Mensaje de Navidad de Nico. [Bip] (Audio) Nico: Hola, Randolph, siento no haber hablado contigo en tanto tiempo. He estado muy ocupado, empecé la escuela, como sabrás, probablemente, como eres ballena no lo sabes, llamo para decirte, para desearte Feliz Navidad. Que tengas una buena Navidad, Adiós Randolph, adiós. MB: Ese es Nico, no supe de él en 18 meses, y hace 2 días dejó un mensaje. Su voz es totalmente diferente, puso a su niñera al teléfono, y ella fue muy amable con Randolph también. Nico es el mejor lector que podía esperar. Quisiera que todos emocionalmente llegasen a ese lugar con las cosas que creo. Tengo suerte, los niños como Nico son los mejores lectores, y merecen las mejores historias que podamos contarles. Muchas gracias. (Aplausos)